Luis Salazar

♥ El Paso, Texas ■ lasalazar@alum.mit.edu 🛅 in/lasm 🕳 https://www.lasm.co

SUMMARY

Business strategy and analytics professional with 14 years of experience. Proven ability to analyze data, identify trends, and develop strategies to drive business objectives. Experienced in designing and executing strategies that are focused on increasing efficiency, productivity, and profitability.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Manager, Commercial Analytics

January 2022 - February 2023, Ridgefield Park, NJ

- Implemented cloud technologies and operational standards within the Commercial Analytics team by leading monthly meetings, incorporating feedback and iterating on the team's processes, improving collaboration and reducing downtime by 14% for the team.
- Tracked weekly performance of 39 sales directors & 44 client success managers to determine progress against predetermined goals & objectives as well as collaborated with Sales Enablement & Compensation team, ensuring delivery of proper training & incentives.
- · Developed Excel tool that decreased forecast reporting time by ~75% for client success team managing 86% of revenue.
- · Using SQL queries & Tableau, prepared reports & visualizations for senior management to understand trends in revenue, invoices, & customer data.

Engagement Manager, Strategy & Analytics Winhall Mill

July 2015 - January 2022, El Paso, TX

- Increased member engagement by 14% and profit margin 5% by leading a team that conducted member surveys (5K respondents), built a financial model that evaluated data from 1MM+ trips and optimized pricing for a car-sharing company.
- Improved conversion rate by 20% and reduced lead-to-close time by 30% (from 9mos to 6mos) by implementing sales process improvements for a construction company SaaS IoT company, including developing buyer personas, financial model, value-based pricing strategy, and sales tool.
- Constructed a financial model and operational strategy to restructure the departments of a rural hospital, leading to a projected annual recurrent savings of \$4.2MM and subsequent acquisition of the hospital by a medical center.
- Implemented cloud technology solutions to improve collaboration between manufacturing stakeholders; decreased production time by 15%; lowered cost of design by 40% through workforce reduction due to technology improvements; and reduced scrap and re-work by 20% at international manufacturing client.

Consultant (Promoted from Analyst in 2013)

Accenture

October 2008 - July 2015, Houston, TX

- Managed 6 offshore resources to build, test, and coordinate activities between 4 teams and 5 separate major ERP systems; managed all issues related to integration and deployment of new ERP application.
- · Headed team of 3 consultants in developing and implementing \$250K technology tool that captured, tracked, and visually monitored 35,000+ stakeholders for leading oil supermajor.
- · Oversaw team of 3 PMO specialists in reviewing ~1,000 artifacts (business requirements, functional specifications, use cases, stories, and test cases) in alignment with the Requirements Traceability Matrix for the design of a major state's health insurance exchange; led analysis of 500+ business requirements and resolved 397 issues by developing and implementing a process to enable the project team to stay within the scope of the project and keep the project on schedule
- · Received 13 awards for Excellence in Client Service.

EDUCATION

Master in Business Administration

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Sloan School of Management \cdot Cambridge, MA \cdot 2015

Master in Engineering and Management

Case Western Reserve University, Weatherhead School of Management \cdot Cleveland, OH \cdot 2008

Bachelor of Science in Biomedical Engineering

The University of Texas at Austin • Austin, TX • 2006

SKILLS

Hard Skills: Data Analysis, Reporting, Financial Analysis, Market Research, Project Management, Process Optimization, Pricing,

SQL, Excel, Access, Salesforce, HubSpot, SalesLoft

CERTIFICATIONS

Revenue Operations Certification

HubSpot Academy ⋅ 2023

HubSpot Marketing Software Certification

HubSpot Academy · 2023

Microsoft Excel Expert

Microsoft Office Specialist · 2022